<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markup language Markdown</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; is a lightweight markup language for creating formatted text using a plain-text editor. John Gruber created Markdown in 2004 as a markup language that is easy to read in its source code form. Markdown is widely used for blogging and instant messaging, and also used elsewhere in online forums, collaborative software, documentation pages, and readme files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial description of Markdown contained ambiguities and raised unanswered questions, causing implementations to both intentionally and accidentally diverge from the original version. This was addressed in 2014 when long-standing Markdown contributors released CommonMark, an unambiguous specification and test suite for Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;markdown-syntax&#34;&gt;Markdown syntax.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a heading, add number signs (#) in front of a word or phrase. The number of number signs you use should correspond to the heading level. For example, to create a heading level three (&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;), use three number signs (e.g., ### My Header).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create paragraphs, use a blank line to separate one or more lines of text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a line break or new line (&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;), end a line with two or more spaces, and then type return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To bold text, add two asterisks or underscores before and after a word or phrase. To bold the middle of a word for emphasis, add two asterisks without spaces around the letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To italicize text, add one asterisk or underscore before and after a word or phrase. To italicize the middle of a word for emphasis, add one asterisk without spaces around the letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To emphasize text with bold and italics at the same time, add three asterisks or underscores before and after a word or phrase. To bold and italicize the middle of a word for emphasis, add three asterisks without spaces around the letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a blockquote, add a &amp;gt; in front of a paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create an ordered list, add line items with numbers followed by periods. The numbers don’t have to be in numerical order, but the list should start with the number one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create an unordered list, add dashes (-), asterisks (*), or plus signs (+) in front of line items. Indent one or more items to create a nested list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add an image, add an exclamation mark (!), followed by alt text in brackets, and the path or URL to the image asset in parentheses. You can optionally add a title in quotation marks after the path or URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-text formulas are created similarly to LaTeX formulas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To convert a Markdown-file to pdf or docx, you can use the following Makefile and use the &amp;ldquo;make all&amp;rdquo; command on the command line.
















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./image1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Makefile&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about this &lt;a href=&#34;https://skillbox.ru/media/code/yazyk-razmetki-markdown-shpargalka-po-sintaksisu-s-primerami/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ru.wikibooks.org/wiki/%D0%9C%D0%B0%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%BC%D0%B0%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%87%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BA%D0%B8%D0%B5_%D1%84%D0%BE%D1%80%D0%BC%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8B_%D0%B2_LaTeX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Week...</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/2nd-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/2nd-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;__hello-everybody__&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello everybody!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is supposed to be a post about the past week, but since there is little new and interesting going on, I can just say that on Monday we had our first test on the Additional Chapters of Queuing Theory, and on Stochastic Processes we started presenting our essays. Everything else is the same. The weather in recent days has not been particularly encouraging, it is getting colder and it often rains, although I love them, I prefer summer ones with thunderstorms. Just last week, the Cantata store had discounts in honor of the company’s birthday, so I was able to purchase new portions of various delicious teas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s probably all, so I wish everyone a good week and see you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/writing-technical-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/writing-technical-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD)&lt;/strong&gt; is a software development approach that aims to improve the speed, efficiency, and reliability of software delivery. This approach involves frequent code integration, automated testing, and continuous deployment of software changes to production.
Before the adoption of CI/CD in the software development industry, the common approach was a traditional, waterfall model of software development.
In this approach, developers worked in silos, with each stage of the software development life cycle completed in sequence. The process typically involved gathering requirements, designing the software, coding, testing, and deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The disadvantages&lt;/em&gt; of this traditional approach include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slow Release Cycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High Failure Rates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited Collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High Cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited Agility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CI/CD emerged as a solution to these disadvantages, by introducing a more agile and collaborative approach to software development. CI/CD enables teams to work together, integrating their code changes frequently, and automating the testing and deployment process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;continuous-integration-ci&#34;&gt;Continuous Integration (CI)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CI is the process of merging all the Developer code changes to a single shared main branch as often as possible, frequently.
Developers merge their code changes, many times a day to the remote Git Repository&amp;rsquo;s main branch. These code changes are then verified and validated by using automation to create builds and run tests on the created builds.
So, the new code changes being pushed are built, integrated and tested in a few minutes, providing immediate feedback to the developer about the code status and any issues.
Continuous Integration ensures that the application is not broken whenever new commits from all the developers are integrated into the Release branch of the Repository, as they are all tested well in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;continuous-delivery-cd&#34;&gt;Continuous Delivery (CD)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery is the practice where the code changes are released frequently in shorter cycles to customers, quickly and reliably.
In continuation with Automated Testing in CI, the application Release process is completely automated so that the code changes can be deployed incrementally at any point of time by just clicking a button (manual trigger).
Generally, shorter release cycles are recommended. Depending on the size of the project, and business requirements, you can configure daily, weekly, fortnightly release schedules.
The shorter the release cycle the easier it is to troubleshoot in case of any issue after deployment onto a Production environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;continuous-deployment-cd&#34;&gt;Continuous Deployment (CD)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery without a manual trigger is Continuous Deployment.
In Continuous Deployment, every code change is directly released to customers without any manual intervention if it successfully passes all the stages of your CI/CD pipeline. So, if there are no failures in any pipeline tests, every code change is available to the customers immediately.
This level of automation is made possible by a combination of several different tools and processes that work together to verify and push the code changes to production.
Once the developer pushes the new code change, it is automatically built, integrated, tested, and directly deployed to the production environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./image1.png&#34; alt=&#34;pic&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The key benefits&lt;/em&gt; of CI/CD include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster Release Cycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved Quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased Collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced Risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost-Effective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, CI/CD emerged as a solution to the limitations of the traditional, linear approach to software development. By introducing a more agile and collaborative approach to software development, CI/CD enables teams to work together, release software more frequently, and respond quickly to customer needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about this &lt;a href=&#34;https://vegastack.com/blog/continuous-integration-continuous-deployment-continuous-delivery/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-ci-cd/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Week...</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;__hello-everybody__&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello everybody!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you already felt all this autumn mood when you want to drink cocoa and watch different movies or read books? I love autumn for that. But since I am actively studying now, it is studying that takes most of the time. This week, for example, I did several laboratory works on Scientific Programming at once. I also watched several videos about neural networks (&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLZHQObOWTQDNU6R1_67000Dx_ZCJB-3pi&amp;amp;si=D_3Cw03OjZDtlBKc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLQVvvaa0QuDcjD5BAw2DxE6OF2tius3V3&amp;amp;si=cLP2sUMQdJywcMUn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), because my future dissertation work assumes the use of a neural network to determine the optimal strategy for the redistribution of resources in a 5G network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have one piece of good news, because last weekend I finally picked up a book from the post office that my friend brought me straight from my beloved Paris. This is a mystical novel by a belgian singer - Loic Nottet, whom I have been listening to since his performance at Eurovision and I am very happy now that I have his book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./image1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Book&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what to read these autumn evenings, then keep a selection of my favorite books:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Victor Hugo &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chitai-gorod.ru/product/sobor-parizhskoy-bogomateri-2513491?productShelf=&amp;amp;shelfIndex=0&amp;amp;productIndex=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;«Notre-Dame de Paris»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erich Maria Remarque &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chitai-gorod.ru/product/triumfalnaya-arka-2602918?productShelf=&amp;amp;shelfIndex=0&amp;amp;productIndex=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;«Arch of Triumph»&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chitai-gorod.ru/product/tri-tovarishcha-2666861?productShelf=&amp;amp;shelfIndex=0&amp;amp;productIndex=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;«Three Comrades»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ray Bradbury &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chitai-gorod.ru/product/4510-po-farengeytu-2822350?productShelf=&amp;amp;shelfIndex=0&amp;amp;productIndex=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;«Fahrenheit 451»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Veniamin Kaverin &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chitai-gorod.ru/product/dva-kapitana-2590405?productShelf=&amp;amp;shelfIndex=0&amp;amp;productIndex=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;«The Two Captains»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guillaume Musso &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chitai-gorod.ru/product/kvartira-v-parizhe-2735645?productShelf=&amp;amp;shelfIndex=0&amp;amp;productIndex=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;«An Apartment in Paris»&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a nice week everyone, bye!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
